Stuart Baker

Group Director of Global Sportsbook Products at Intralot

stuart@bettingbaker.com

Summary

20+ years experience in the Betting & Gaming industry.

- 2 years B2B/B2C Chief Product Officer
- 2 years B2B Head of Product
- 2 years B2B Director of Product Development
- 1 year B2C Head of Sportsbook and Business Development
- 6 years in B2C eGaming Product/Business Development.
- 4 years as a Fixed Odds Sports Trader.
- 3 Years as a Sports Spread Betting Trader.

Specialties: Comprehensive experience and knowledge of the Gambling and eGaming industry with a proven track record in Product Management, Product Owner, Chief Product Owner, Sportsbook and Horse Racing Management, Odds Compilation, Trading and Trading Software, Risk Management, Customer Profiling, Social Gaming, Jurisdictional Licensing, New Business and New Product Delivery.

Experience

Group Director of Global Sportsbook Products at Intralot

June 2016 - Present (10 months)

Chief Product Officer at BetConstruct

February 2014 - June 2016 (2 years 5 months)

Building a new Gaming and Sportsbook Platform from the ground up ... don't try this at home.

Armenia/UK (B2B) - Chief Product Owner for New Multi-Product Platform and New Sportsbook.

Change to Agile (DAD). Trading Tools and Processes. Liability Management. Risk Management. Odds Feed. Jurisdictional Compliance. CRM. Multi-Product Bonus Engine. CMS. Affiliate Program. Partner Management. Pre-Sales. Online. Retail.

Head of Sportsbook Product at OpenBet Ltd

October 2011 - October 2013 (2 years 1 month)

Owner of Sportsbook roadmap - Trading Interface, Liabilities, Telebet, Feeds, Settlement Engine, Bet Placement, Jurisdictional Compliance, Front End data delivery ...

Director Development at Sportradar AG

September 2009 - August 2011 (2 years)

Development & Sales - Live Betting Solutions, Sports Data (Live Scores, Statistics, Fixtures, Results), Hosted Solutions, Live Match Centres, Trading Tools, Mobile Solutions, Fantasy Betting, 3D Tracking, Fraudulent Betting Monitoring ...

Consultant - Sportsbook & Business Development Director at Begawin.com

September 2008 - September 2009 (1 year 1 month)

Head of Sportsbook - Trading, Marketing, Operations, Budget and P&L responsibility.

Development - New Products, New Business.

Head of New Product Development at Ladbrokes

September 2004 - September 2008 (4 years 1 month)

New Products, New Business, New Ventures, New Partners, Enhancing existing products.

Sportsbook, Games, Bingo, Financial Betting, Cross Product ...

Head of Sportsbook Development at Ladbrokes

December 2003 - September 2004 (10 months)

Online Development Manager at Ladbrokes

April 2003 - December 2003 (9 months)

Senior Risk Manager / Trader at Bet Direct

March 1998 - April 2003 (5 years 2 months)

Sports Spread Betting Trader at City Index

June 1995 - March 1998 (2 years 10 months)

Test Scores

Verbal & Numerical Reasoning

July 2006 Score:99th Percentile

In the top 1% as measured across Pan European executives

Volunteer Experience

Team & Pitch Coordinator at Cronk Cunis U21 National Rugby Festival

August 2006 - Present

Annual volunteer and general dogsbody

Stage Volunteer at Tour of Britain 2014

September 2014 - Present

Team member at Stage 6 - Bath to Hemel Hempstead

Games Maker at London 2012

August 2012 - Present

Team member in the Transport Team at the Media and Broadcast Centres in the Olympic Park.

Skills & Expertise

Betting

Gaming Industry

Product Development

Sports

New Business Development

Trading

Sportsbook

Online Gambling

Online Gaming

E-commerce

Casino

Product Management

Gambling

Affiliate Marketing

Mobile Devices

Online Advertising

Team Management

User Experience

Gaming

Business Development

Digital Marketing

Start-ups

Bingo

Management

B₂B

E-payments

Consulting

Software Development

Mobile Applications

Strategy

Education

University of York

BSc, Economics, 1989 - 1993

Activities and Societies: 1st XV Rugby, 1st XI Cricket

Cranleigh School

Maths Scholar, 1983 - 1988

Handcross Park School

Certifications

Disciplined Agile Delivery Product Owner

Disciplined Agile Consortium July 2014

Key Individual Certificate

Alderney Gambling Control Commission License 150.04 C2A December 2014

Certified Disciplined Agilist (CDA)

Disciplined Agile Consortium July 2015

Stuart Baker

Group Director of Global Sportsbook Products at Intralot

stuart@bettingbaker.com



2 people have recommended Stuart

"Stuart was the biggest reason I accepted an offer at OpenBet and it was an honor working with him. Always calm and thoughtful he has the natural ability to choose the best solution to any given problem and align my road-map to the company's strategy and goals while keeping work fun. He builds moral within his team and has natural insight into product management and people management making him an asset to any business. I know Stuart puts people first and for this reason people want to work with him. To me, Stuart is the most knowledgeable person I know in the Sportsbook and gaming market and I cannot thank him enough for taking the time to ensure I had a full understanding of my requirements before implementation. Complicated terms were made simple by his creative (and fun) explanations. If asked, I'd work with Stuart every day of the week! If you are looking for a product leader - look no further, you have found who you are looking for."

- Brendon Spronk, reported to Stuart at OpenBet Ltd

"Stuart is the ideal person to have by your side when the heat is on. You can rely on him to keep a cool head and identify a way forward when the pressure is mounting, relishing any task that requires some quick, logical thinking to reach a solution. I worked with Stuart for a couple of years, initially as a direct report and then with a dotted line after a restructure. He offered me tremendous amount of support as both a manager and a colleague in all the projects we worked on and I would not hesitate to work with him again."

— Michael Morgan, reported to Stuart at Ladbrokes

Contact Stuart on LinkedIn